{
  "1": {
	"Question": "What year did the flood occur?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "1513 BCE",
	  "607 BCE"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "2370 BCE",
	"Refernece": "https://www.jw.org/finder?wtlocale=E&docid=1200001150&srctype=wol&srcid=share&par=2"
  },
  "2": {
	"Question": "What was the prophet Daniel's Babylonian name?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Fred",
	  "Shadrach",
	  "Nebuchadnezzar"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Belteshazzar",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200001117#h=5"
  },
  "3": {
	"Question": "How big was Noah's ark?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "800 sq ft",
	  "As big as the Titanic"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "300 cubits long, 50 cubits wide, and 30 cubits high",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "4": {
	"Question": "What year did the Bible Students change their name to Jehovah's Witnesses?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "1935",
	  "1914"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "1931",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "5": {
	"Question": "Which one of Jesus's apostles saw a vision of unclean animals and was told to 'slaughter and eat' them?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Paul",
	  "James"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Peter",
	"Refernece": "Acts 10:11-13"
  },
  "6": {
	"Question": "What was the first kind of bird that Noah released from the ark to check if the waters had receded?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Dove",
	  "Ostrich"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Raven",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "7": {
	"Question": "How many stones did David select to prepare in fighting Goliath?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "6",
	  "7"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "5",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "8": {
	"Question": "Who replaced Judas after his betrayal?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Paul",
	  "Timothy"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Matthias",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1102009043?q=judas+replaced&p=par"
  },
  "9": {
	"Question": "Who baptized Jesus?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "He baptised himself",
	  "Joseph"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "John the Baptist",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "10": {
	"Question": "In Nehemiah's time, how many days did it take to complete the rebuilding of the walls of Jererusalem?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "14",
	  "49",
	  "157"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "52",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200003212#h=12"
  },
  "11": {
	"Question": "Who was the apostle Andrew's brother?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "James",
	  "Bartholomew"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Peter",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000273#h=3"
  },
  "12": {
	"Question": "What year was Aaron born?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "1513 BCE",
	  "607 BCE",
	  "2370 BCE"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "1597 BCE",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000005#h=3"
  },
  "13": {
	"Question": "Before marrying King David, Abigail was married to a man who's name means \"senseless\" or \"stupid\". What was his name?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Nebuchadnezzar",
	  "Korah",
	  "Achan"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Nabal",
	"Refernece": "1 Samuel 25:25"
  },
  "14": {
	"Question": "How old was Abram when he was given the name Abraham?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "53",
	  "33",
	  "77"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "99",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000060"
  },
  "15": {
	"Question": "Shem and Abraham's lives overlapped.",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "False"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "True",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000060#h=6"
  },
  "16": {
	"Question": "How old was Abram when he began to move to the land of Canaan?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "90",
	  "62",
	  "45"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "75",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000060#h=9"
  },
  "17": {
	"Question": "Which man's home did the Ark of the Covenant remain for 70 years before being transferred to Jerusalem?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "King David",
	  "Samuel",
	  "King Solomon"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Abinadab",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000046#h=4"
  },
  "18": {
	"Question": "When Achan took from the city of Jericho what \"[belonged] to Jehovah\" (Joshua 6:17), what items did he not take?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "A garment from Shinar",
	  "50-shekel gold bar",
	  "200 silver shekels"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "An acacia wood table",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000074#h=4"
  },
  "19": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Acts?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Paul",
	  "Matthew"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Luke",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000084"
  },
  "20": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Judges?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Sampson",
	  "David",
	  "Moses"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Samuel",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "21": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Ruth?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Ruth",
	  "Nehemiah",
	  "Solomon"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Samuel",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "22": {
	"Question": "Who wrote 1 Kings and 2 Kings?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "David",
	  "Solomon",
	  "Samuel"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Jeremiah",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "23": {
	"Question": "Who wrote 1 Chronicles and 2 Chronicles?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Moses",
	  "David",
	  "Paul"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Ezra",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "24": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Esther?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Esther",
	  "Moses",
	  "Ezra"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Mordecai",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "25": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Ecclesiastes?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "David",
	  "Paul",
	  "Jeremiah"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Solomon",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "26": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Lamentations?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Solomon",
	  "David",
	  "Samuel"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Jeremiah",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "27": {
	"Question": "Who wrote the Bible book of Revelation?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Peter",
	  "Matthew",
	  "Mark"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "John",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "28": {
	"Question": "What location was the Ark of the Covenant kept in the temple?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "On the roof",
	  "In the inner courtyard",
	  "Between the pillars"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Most Holy",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "29": {
	"Question": "Who was Jacob's son Asher's mother?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Rachel",
	  "Leah"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Zilpah",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "30": {
	"Question": "In ancient Israel, what was a the nearest male relative called who was under obligation to atone for one who had been killed?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Mr. Revenge",
	  "Avenger of Life",
	  "Redeemer of Blood"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Avenger of Blood",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000473"
  },
  "31": {
	"Question": "What is the name of Jacob's 12th son?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Joseph",
	  "Asher",
	  "Judah"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Benjamin",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "32": {
	"Question": "What is the name of Jacob's firstborn son?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Naphtali",
	  "Dan",
	  "Joseph"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Reuben",
	"Refernece": null
  },
  "33": {
	"Question": "Only three Roman Caesars who were ruling during the period covered by the Christian Greek Scriptures were mentioned by name in the Bible. Which name is not included among them?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Augustus",
	  "Tiberius",
	  "Claudius"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Caligula",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000852"
  },
  "34": {
	"Question": "When Moses sent out the 12 spies to survey the land of Canaan, how many days did they spend there?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "150",
	  "14",
	  "30"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "40",
	"Refernece": "https://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200000863"
  },
  "35": {
	"Question": "The statue of what type of angel was put on top of the Ark of the Covenant?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Archangel",
	  "Seraph"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Cherub",
	"Refernece": "https://www.jw.org/finder?srcid=jwlshare&wtlocale=E&prefer=lang&docid=1200000945"
  },
  "36": {
	"Question": "Who was the 1st non-Jew to have Holy Spirit fall upon him?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Silas",
	  "Timothy"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Cornelius",
	"Refernece": "Acts 10:44,45\nhttps://wol.jw.org/en/wol/d/r1/lp-e/1200001041?q=Cornelius&p=par#h=4"
  },
  "37": {
	"Question": "Which political ruler did Jehovah have an angel strike down with worms so that he died?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Tiberius Caesar",
	  "Nebuchadnezzar"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Harod Agrippa",
	"Refernece": "Acts 12:23"
  },
  "38": {
	"Question": "Who lived for 969 years?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Adam",
	  "Noah"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Methuselah",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 5:27"
  },
  "39": {
	"Question": "What animal did Jesus liken King Herod to and why?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Donkey because of his stubbornness",
	  "Lion since he was a King"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Fox because of his craftiness",
	"Refernece": "Luke 13:32"
  },
  "40": {
	"Question": "How many years did Jehovah strike Nebuchadnezzar with insanity?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Six",
	  "Ten",
	  "Two"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Seven",
	"Refernece": "Daniel 4:32"
  },
  "41": {
	"Question": "Which profit did Jehovah have walk around naked and barefoot?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Moses",
	  "Jeremiah",
	  "Elisha"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Isaiah",
	"Refernece": "Isaiah 20:3"
  },
  "42": {
	"Question": "What insect did John the baptizer eat along with honey?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Ants",
	  "Bees"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Locusts",
	"Refernece": "Matthew 3:4"
  },
  "43": {
	"Question": "How many silver coins did Judas Iscariot receive for betraying Jesus?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "42",
	  "100",
	  "2"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "30",
	"Refernece": "Matthew 26:15"
  },
  "44": {
	"Question": "What kind of bird brought food to the profit Elijah?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Ostriches",
	  "Chickens",
	  "Finches"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Ravens",
	"Refernece": "1 Kings 17:6"
  },
  "45": {
	"Question": "Which city's name means confusion?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Ur",
	  "Damascus"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Babel",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 11:9"
  },
  "46": {
	"Question": "Adam and Eve used what kind of leaves to make clothes?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Oak tree leaves",
	  "Elm tree leaves"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Fig leaves",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 3:7"
  },
  "47": {
	"Question": "Which directions were the cherubs posted to guard the garden of Eden?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "West",
	  "North",
	  "South"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "East",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 3:24"
  },
  "48": {
	"Question": "How many angels did Jehovah send to warn Lot to leave Sodom?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "1",
	  "4",
	  "7"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "2",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 19:1"
  },
  "49": {
	"Question": "What color was the stew that Esau sold his birth right for?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "White",
	  "The Account Doesn't Say"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Red",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 25:30"
  },
  "50": {
	"Question": "What body part was dislocated when Jacob wrestled with an angel?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Shoulder",
	  "Big toe",
	  "Knee"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Hip",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 32:25"
  },
  "51": {
	"Question": "What did Joseph's brothers do to make Jacob think his son was dead?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "They told him he drank bad wine"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "They dipped his coat in goat's blood",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 37:31"
  },
  "52": {
	"Question": "Which brother of Joseph's didn't want him killed?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Judah",
	  "Asher"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Reuben",
	"Refernece": "Genesis 37:22,29"
  },
  "53": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank. (Matthew 23 : 13)\n\"Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, ___ because you shut up the Kingdom of the heavens before men...\"",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Idiots!",
	  "Morons!"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Hypocrites!",
	"Refernece": "Matthew 23 : 13"
  },
  "54": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank (4 words)\n'Ponder over these things _ _ _ _, so that your advancement may be plainly seen by all people.'",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Read all of them",
	  "Do all of them",
	  "Be motivated by them"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Be absorbed in them",
	"Refernece": "1 Timothy 4:15"
  },
  "55": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank.\n'Look! The eye of Jehovah watches over those _____ him, Those waiting for his loyal love.'",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Loving",
	  "Obeying",
	  "Watching"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Fearing",
	"Refernece": "Psalm 33:18"
  },
  "56": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank.\n'Taste and see that Jehovah is ____'",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Tasty",
	  "Salty",
	  "Righteous"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Good",
	"Refernece": "Psalm 34:8"
  },
  "57": {
	"Question": "Finish the song lyric. (4 words)\n'The living and true God—The God of all creation In ev'ry generation _ _ _ _'",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Jehovah is my God",
	  "Jehovah is my Friend"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Jehovah is your name",
	"Refernece": "Sing out Joyfully Song 2"
  },
  "58": {
	"Question": "Finish the song. (5 words)\n‘When we preach, when we teach, we have confidence because ___ ____ ___ ____ ___.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "You will help us succeed",
	  "We have prayed for help"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "It’s on you we rely",
	"Refernece": "Song 3"
  },
  "59": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blanks from this kingdom song.\n‘Where could I hide from you, Jehovah,Or be concealed, be hidden from your face?Not in the ____ nor in the highest heaven, Not in the ____ nor in the __ there is no place.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Tomb / Dark / Water",
	  "Grave / Dark / Ocean",
	  "Grave / Dark / Light"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Grave / Dark / Sea",
	"Refernece": "Song 5"
  },
  "60": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank. \n“We urge you, brothers, to warn the disorderly, speak consolingly to those who are depressed, support the weak, be ____ toward all.”",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Kind",
	  "Good",
	  "Forgiving"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Patient",
	"Refernece": "1 Thessalonians 5:14"
  },
  "61": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank from this scripture. \n'Love ‘does not look for its own ___.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Desire",
	  "Advantage",
	  "Benefit"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Interest",
	"Refernece": "1 Corinthians 13:5"
  },
  "62": {
	"Question": "What nationality was the woman Jesus spoke to at the well?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Greek",
	  "Jewish",
	  "Phoenician"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Samaritan",
	"Refernece": "John 4 :9"
  },
  "63": {
	"Question": "What book of the Bible had the Ethiopian been reading, when Philip witnessed to him?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Matthew",
	  "Philippians",
	  "Job"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Isaiah",
	"Refernece": "Acts 8:30"
  },
  "64": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank for this song lyric. \n‘Jehovah, our ____, Our strength and our might,Your name we make known Both day and night.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Friend",
	  "God"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Rock",
	"Refernece": "Song 7"
  },
  "65": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank for this song lyric. \n‘Jehovah is our refuge, Our God in whom we trust. His ____ is our shelter; Remain in it we must.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Word, Love, Name"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Shadow",
	"Refernece": "Song 8"
  },
  "66": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank for this song lyric. \n‘Let the heavens rejoice, Let the ____ joyful be, For Jehovah has become our King!’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "People",
	  "World",
	  "Meek"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Earth",
	"Refernece": "Song 9"
  },
  "67": {
	"Question": "How many fruitage of the spirit are there?",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "7",
	  "8",
	  "10"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "9",
	"Refernece": "Galations 5:22,23"
  },
  "68": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank. (Galatians 6:9)\n'So let us not give up in doing what is fine, for in due time we will reap if we do not ___ out.'",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Give",
	  "Poop"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Tire",
	"Refernece": "Galations 6:9"
  },
  "69": {
	"Question": "Complete the scripture. (Proverbs 14:12)\n’There is a way that seems right to a man, But in the end it leads to ____.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Trouble",
	  "Tacos",
	  "Unrighteousnesses"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Death",
	"Refernece": "Proverbs 14:12"
  },
  "70": {
	"Question": "Complete the scripture. (Proverbs 14:15)\n‘The ____ person believes every word, But the shrewd one ponders each step.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Stupid",
	  "Wicked",
	  "Unrighteous"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Naïve",
	"Refernece": "Proverbs 14:15"
  },
  "71": {
	"Question": "Complete the scripture. (Proverbs 14:17)\n‘The one who is quick to anger acts foolishly, But the man who thinks things out is ____.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Wise",
	  "Kind",
	  "Mild"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Hated",
	"Refernece": "Proverbs 14:17"
  },
  "72": {
	"Question": "Fill in the blank. \n‘... Jehovah’s angel appeared to Joseph in a dream, saying Get up, take the young child and his mother and flee to ____, and stay there until I give you word, for Herod is about to search for the young child to kill him.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Bethlehem",
	  "Nazareth",
	  "Fiji"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Egypt",
	"Refernece": "Matthew 2:13"
  },
  "73": {
	"Question": "Finish the scripture.\n‘So my word that goes out of my mouth will be.  It will not ___ to me without results, But it will certainly accomplish whatever is my ____, And it will have sure success in what I send it to do.‘",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Come / Wish",
	  "Return / Purpose",
	  "Come / Plan"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Return / Delight",
	"Refernece": "Isaiah 55:11"
  },
  "74": {
	"Question": "Finish the scripture. (2 words)\n‘They will not cause any harm Or any ruin in all my __ ___, Because the earth will certainly be filled with the knowledge of Jehovah As the waters cover the sea.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Paradise earth",
	  "Restored land"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Holy Mountain",
	"Refernece": "Isaiah 11:9"
  },
  "75": {
	"Question": "Finish the scripture. \n‘A ____ will grow out of the stump of ___, And a sprout from his roots will bear fruit.’",
	"Other Multiple Choice Answers": [
	  "Limb / Trees",
	  "Branch / David"
	],
	"Correct Answer": "Twig / Jesse",
	"Refernece": "Isaiah 11:1"
  }
}
